ILGWU. President's Office records, 5780/154
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. President's Office records
1981-1985.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. President's Office;
Mazur, Jay.
5780/154
10.11 cubic feet
10 linear feet
Records
Consists of files maintained by Jay Mazur during his tenure as Secretary-Treasurer of the ILGWU. Included are correspondence and memoranda with staff at the ILGWU's departments, as well as regional departments, joint councils, and local unions. Records also include agreements and documentation relating to various investments and funds.
5510764
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Jay Mazur was born in New York City on May 21, 1932. Mazur began working for the ILGWU at the age of 18, beginning with organizing and educational work with Local 22 in New York City. He was Director of Organization and Education for Local 40, then Director of Organization for Local 23, before becoming Assistant Manager of the newly merged Locals 23 and 25 in 1964. From 1973 to 1983, Mazur was Manager of Local 23-25, the Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union. Elected General Secretary-Treasurer of the ILGWU in 1983, Mazur served in that capacity until he succeeded Sol C. Chaikin as President of the ILGWU in 1986. He served as President of the ILGWU until 1995, when it merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers of America to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). From 1995 until his retirement in 2001, Mazur was president of UNITE. In addition to his work for the ILGWU and UNITE, Mazur served on the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO, as well as the Industrial Union Department of the AFL-CIO.
Scope and Contents
Consists of files maintained by Jay Mazur during his tenure as Secretary-Treasurer of the ILGWU. Included are correspondence and memoranda with staff at the ILGWU's departments, as well as regional departments, joint councils, and local unions. Records also include agreements and documentation relating to various investments and funds.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/059. ILGWU. Local 23-25 records
5780/059 P. ILGWU. Local 23-25 photographs
5780/059 PUBS. ILGWU. Local 23-25 publications
5780/095. ILGWU. Local 23-25 records
5780/095 G. ILGWU. Local 23-25 graphics
5780/203. ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. President's Office.
5510764
- Frontlash, 1985 - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Concerning youth education, voter participation, and Labor Resource Service fundraising.
- Funds for New Priorities, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Concerning the March 14th, 1985 Annual Dinner. Includes a speech.
- Garment Industry Advisory Committee [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, memorandums, and agendas.
- Garment Industry Advisory Committee [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Garment Center Rally - Expenses, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Advisory Council [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Minutes and discussions from the meeting.
- General Advisory Council [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Minutes and Discussion.
- Garment Center Rally, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes census and rally plans.
- Garment Center Economic Security, 1983 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes checks and newsletters.
- Garment Industry Development Corporation [Part 1 of 3], 1983 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Reports, correspondence, and accounting.
- Garment Industry Development Corporation [Part 2 of 3], 1983 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Garment Industry Development Corporation [Part 3 of 3], 1983 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- GIDC Checks / Day Care Center [Part 1 of 3], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Correspondence and minutes on various subjects.
- GIDC Checks / Day Care Center [Part 2 of 3], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- GIDC Checks / Day Care Center [Part 3 of 3], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- GIDC Checks, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Garment Center Study - Herbert Sturz, 1983 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Concerning Chinatown Day Care Center.
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 1 of 6], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Correspondence and notes.
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 2 of 6], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Handwritten notes.
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 3 of 6], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  June 1985. Reports.
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 4 of 6], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 5 of 6], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  December 1985.
- General Executive Board Meeting [Part 6 of 6], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Correspondence and financial reports.
- Group Life Insurance, Incorporated, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Correspondence concerning salary changes.
- Green, Paula Advertising, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Cost of print ads.
- Godson, Roy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  "Soviet Manipulation of the Media: Fact or Fiction".
- Industrial Loft Advisory Council, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Correspondence and minutes.
- Icelandic Federation of Labor [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Correspondence and Hotel Saga meeting.
- Icelandic Federation of Labor [Part 2 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Includes a directory, pamphlets, and a newsletter.
- Iceland Federation of Labor 35th Congress, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  November 25th and 26th. Copies of speech.
- Hotels, 1983 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Omni Park Hotel and Sheraton City Squire Hotel.
- Histadrut [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Correspondence and newsletters.
- Histadrut [Part 2 of 2], 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Pamphlets, correspondence, and notes.
- Homework [Part 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Statements, comments, correspondence, and an essay on "Industrial Homework."
- Homework [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Newsletters, statements, and correspondence on "Industrial Homework."
- Havlicek, Franklin J., 1984 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Letter with resume attached to Jay Mazur.
- Health Futures Group, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Concerning a health care program.
- Trustee Meeting, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  December 18th, 12:30PM - 500 Seventh Avenue - 500 Club. Includes a health services plan report.
- Immigrants and Entrepreneurs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Drafts on Chinatown.
- Immigration, 1983 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Essays. Reports, and newsletters about immigration.
- Imports [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Various documents concerning the impact of imports.
- Imports [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ILGWU - History, 1983 - 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Thirty page draft of the ILGWU's history.
- ILGWU - Data Center, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Concerning its use and its closure.
- ILGWU - Strike Fund, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Includes a copy of the ILGWU part of the constitution concerning strikes.
- Policy, 1984 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Concerning information about employees and dues.
- Local Unions, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Locations.
- Import Roll Back [Part 1 of 3], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Memorandums and correspondence.
- Import Roll Back [Part 2 of 3], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Import Roll Back [Part 3 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Correspondence.
- Holiday Pay Commission, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Agreement.
- Herald Square Rally, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  April 10th, 1985. Rally concerning imports.
- Imports - Articles, 1984 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Newspaper Articles.
- Imports and Trade Speech Material, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Includes reports and articles.
- Frances Wang, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Frances Wang was an ILGWU organizer who went missing during her investigation of sweatshops.
- Personnel Review Committee, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Concerning salary adjustments.
- Gus Tyler's Writings, 1983 - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Writing on trade policy and economy. Includes a photocopy of a newspaper biography of Gus Tyler.
- Personnel [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Various correspondence, memos, and reports concerning different ILGWU members and groups.
- Personnel [Part 2 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NY Organizers [Part 1 of 4], 1983 - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  The Future of Organizing.
- NY Organizers [Part 2 of 4], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  A union labor report entitled "Labor Relations Consultants: Issues, Trends, and Controversies."
- NY Organizers [Part 3 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Various memos, recommendations, correspondence, lists, and reports on organizing.
- NY Organizers [Part 4 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Research Department, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Statements of Herman Starobin and reports.
- Organization Directors Meeting, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  December 4th through the 6th.
- Finance Department, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Breakdown of local unions.
- Health and Safety Department, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Union Health Center.
- Lockiec Meeting, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Memorandums and a report.
- Legislative Department, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Advanced Training Staff, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Training institution. Lists of staff members.
- Business Agent Training Program, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Memos and correspondence.
- Collection Control Department, 1983 - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Model collection procedures.
- Retirees, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Letters from retirees.
- Education Department, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Correspondence, memorandums, and a documentary proposal.
- Gus Tyler, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Correspondence, memorandums, and articles.
- Phelps Dodge Corporate Campaign [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Correspondence and information kit.
- Phelps Dodge Corporate Campaign [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Calendar.
- International Affairs, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Includes a report, correspondence from the AFL- CIO, and a summary of the AFL-CIO International Affairs Director's meeting.
- Radio Editorial, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Transcripts of the WINS and WCBS radio reports on your testimony before the UDC.
- Real Estate, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Various documents on rents and leases.
- 401(k) Plan, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Clippings and 401(k) Deferred Compensation Plan.
- Salary Comparison, 1983 - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Series of print-outs involving individual salary charges during March 1984 and July 1983.
- National Retirement Fund [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Summary Plans and clipping on pensions.
- National Retirement Fund [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Reports including a Withdrawal Liability
- Death Benefits Fund [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Reports, applications, and summaries.
- Death Benefits Fund [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Puerto Rico, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Correspondence and newspaper clippings.
- Auditing Department, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Benefit Funds, 1983 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Funds Merger, 1983 - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  Memorandums.
- Western Canada, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 1 of 10], 1981 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Labor agreement, maps, press releases, statements and balances, and bylaws.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 2 of 10], 1981 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 3 of 10], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Agreement and lay-off of Pietro Antonelli.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 4 of 10], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Memorandums
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 5 of 10], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  District Council. Correspondence and memos.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 6 of 10], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  District Council. Finances.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 7 of 10], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Breakdown of salaries and expenses.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 8 of 10], 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Negotiations, agreements, and breakdowns of salaries and expenses.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 9 of 10], 1983 - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Collective bargaining agreements and finances.
- Western Canadian Regions [Part 10 of 10], 1983 - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Collective bargaining agreement, correspondence, finances, and decisions.
- Puerto Rico - Health and Welfare Fund [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Minutes, itinerary, and speeches.
- Puerto Rico - Health and Welfare Fund [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Speech, minutes, and financial statement.
- Steven Nutter, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Study of California Apparel Industry
- Toronto Cloak and Dress District [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Correspondence, reports, and a copy of a newspaper clipping.
- Toronto Cloak and Dress District [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Quebec Joint Council, 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Correspondence, notes, and a statement.
- Toronto Trip, 1984 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Quebec Joint Council [Part 1 of 2], 1981 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  General correspondence, a study on working conditions, and investigations on organized crime.
- Quebec Joint Council [Part 2 of 2], 1981 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Collective Bargaining Agreements (one in English and one in French)
- Montreal News Clippings, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Photocopies of clippings.
- Montreal Gilles Gauthier, 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Negotiations and correspondence.
- Legal [Part 1 of 3], 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Correspondence and memorandums.
- Legal [Part 2 of 3], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Independent Agreements sent to all regional directors, managers, and ILGWU attorneys.
- Legal [Part 3 of 3], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Correspondence about the union newspaper called "Justice", memorandums, and a paper entitled, "External Law: The Albatross of Arbitrators".
- South Africa [Part 1 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Draft resolution, AFL-CIO policy towards South Africa, news paper articles, and reports on South African unions.
- South Africa [Part 2 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  United Nations report on Apartheid, Justice newspapers, correspondence, and magazine articles.
- South Africa [Part 3 of 3], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Conferences about South Africa
- Portugal Speech, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Remarks by Max M. Kampelman in the International Conference Democratic Challenge in Latin America in Lisbon, Portugal.
- Investment Committee Meeting, 1983 - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Department procedures and agenda.
- International Textile, Garment, and Leather Workers' Federation, 1984 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Report on activities, statements, notes on applicants for general secretary position, and correspondence.
- Young Social Democrats, 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Correspondence
- Zensen, 1983 - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Correspondence, anniversary agenda, speech, and article.
- Yiddish National Theater, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Concerning the rental of Roosevelt Auditorium.
- Max Zimney, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  General Counsel Speech - The New York Chapter of the IRRA on October 11th.
- Southeast Region, 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, maps, memos, agendas, and various documents concerning the Southeast Region.
- Miami, 1983 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, maps, statements, and hand-written notes.
- Western States [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Personnel and immigration; Correspondence concerning California unions.
- Western States [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  A report entitled "The Apparel Industry: The Other California" and hand written notes.
- Upper South, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Correspondence and includes copies of certificates.
- New England Region, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Correspondence and memorandums. Includes a copy of a newspaper clipping and a retirement party invitation.
- New York State District, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Personnel, restructuring, organization reports, and memorandums.
- New Jersey Region [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Correspondence and political activity. Includes a report.
- New Jersey Region [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Personnel information.
- San Francisco Area, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Organizing campaign blueprint, lease agreements, reports, correspondence, and a map.
- Philadelphia and South New Jersey Area, 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Personnel and strike authorization.
- Northeast, Western Pennsylvania, and Ohio District, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Documents from director Sol Hoffman. Includes personnel lists and memos.
- Central States Region, 1983 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Correspondence and an agreement.
- Midwest Region [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Lou Montenegro.
- Midwest Region [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Firms, welfare, health programs, personnel.
- Local 23 - 25, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Statements, agreements, pamphlets, and newsletters.
- Local 89 - 22 - 1, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Correspondence, reports, and an agreement.
- Local 99, 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Local 91 - 105, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Local 66 - 40, 1983 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Correspondence and personnel.
- Local 102 [Part 1 of 3], 1982 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Contract modifications, dental insurance, and other correspondence.
- Local 102 [Part 2 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Memorandums on agreements, resumes, negotiations, and other correspondence.
- Local 102 [Part 3 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Retirement fund, Speadmark Contract, curriculum vitae, handwritten notes, and miscellaneous correspondence.
- Local 102 Negotiations, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Negotiations, agreements, and handwritten notes.
- Local 91, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Gerson and Gerson.
- Local 155, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Correspondence, statements, and newsletters.
- Local 98 Negotiations, 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Summary of agreements and resolutions.
- Local 132 Agreement, 1983 - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Personnel and resolutions.
- Local 132 - 98, 1984 - 1985 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Proposals and notes.
- Local 153, 1982 - 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Agreement and notes.
- Speeches – President Chaikin [Part 1 of 4], 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Correspondence and drafts of speeches.
- Speeches – President Chaikin [Part 2 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Statements and testimonies.
- Speeches – President Chaikin [Part 3 of 4], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Speeches before subcommittee on trade, AFL-CIO Civil Rights Conference, subcommittee on labor, and at Columbia University.
- Speeches – President Chaikin [Part 4 of 4], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Regarding the investigation of U.S. Trade Related Employment, Rational Development Policy, and Subminimum wages.
- Jay Mazur [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Testimonials, interviews, statements, and remarks.
- Jay Mazur [Part 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Local 23 - 25 [Part 1 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Health and Welfare Fund.
- Local 23 - 25 [Part 2 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Local 23 - 25 [Part 3 of 4], 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Local 23 - 25 [Part 4 of 4], 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- New York Skirt and Sportswear Association, 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Concerning health and welfare.
- CNN Interviews, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Interview conducted August 29th at 11:30AM. Includes interview transcripts, AFL-CIO newspapers, and handwritten notes.
- Ladies Apparel Contractors, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, 1982 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)